{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How many squares are there on a chess board?",
      "options": [32, 64, 54, 36],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which piece can never move backward?",
      "options": ["the knight", "the bishop", "the pawn", "the king"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What best describes the movement of the knight?",
      "options": [
        "L-shaped",
        "up and down, left and right",
        "diagonnally",
        "forward only"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What does castling allow?",
      "options": [
        "the king can move two squares",
        "the king moves to relative safety",
        "the rooks are closer to being connected",
        "all of the above"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What rule does NOT apply to castling?",
      "options": [
        "the king must have moved before",
        "the king must not be in check",
        "the king cannot move through check",
        "the rook must not have moved before"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "How long are the longest diagonals on the board?",
      "options": ["6 squares", "7 squares", "8 squares", "9 squares"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which rule allows a pawn to capture a pawn that is behind itself?",
      "options": ["checkmate", "check", "capture", "en passant"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which square does the White King sit on in the starting position?",
      "options": ["a1", "e1", "d1", "f1"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which square does the Black Queen sit on in the starting position?",
      "options": ["a8", "e8", "d8", "f8"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which player, considered the greatest of all time, gave up the title of world champion?",
      "options": [
        "Gary Kasparov",
        "Emmanuel Lasker",
        "Bobby Fischer",
        "Magnus Carlsen"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    }
  ]
}
